let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Advantage of UNION over STRUCTURE is _______________.",
    answer: "b.) Memory Location",
    options: [
      "a.) Memory Storage",
      "b.) Memory Location",
      "c.) Memory Screen",
      "d.) None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Maximum number of elements in the array declaration 'int arr[5][8];' is ________.",
    answer: "b.) 32",
    options: [
      "a.) 28",
      "b.) 32",
      "c.) 35",
      "d.) 40"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Array subscripts in C always start at __________.",
    answer: "d.) 0",
    options: [
      "a.) 1",
      "b.) -1",
      "c.) as per programmer",
      "d.) 0"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which is the correct way to declare a pointer?",
    answer: "c.) int *ptr;",
    options: [
      "a.) int ptr;",
      "b.) *int *ptr;",
      "c.) int *ptr;",
      "d.) *int ptr;"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Output of the printf('2.3f\n',17.23478) will be _____________.",
    answer: "d.) 17.23",
    options: [
      "a.) 17.23478",
      "b.) 17.235",
      "c.) 17.2348",
      "d.) 17.23"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What will be the value of the following: 1. floor(5.8) 2. floor(-5.8)",
    answer: "b.) 5, -6",
    options: [
      "a.) -5,-6",
      "b.) 5, -6",
      "c.) -5,6",
      "d.) 5,6"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What would be the value of X after execution of the following statements? int x,y=10; char z='a'; x=y+z;",
    answer: "d.) 10a",
    options: [
      "a.) Invalid",
      "b.) 17",
      "c.) 107",
      "d.) 10a"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What will be the output the following: int *i, *j, a=12, b=2, c ; c= (a=a+b, b=a/b, a=a*b, b=a-b); i= &c; printf ('%d',--(*i));",
    answer: "b.) 92",
    options: [
      "a.) 93",
      "b.) 92",
      "c.) 91",
      "d.) 90"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What will be the output of the following program? switch(a/a%b) { case 1: a=a-b; case 2: a=a+b; case 3: a=a*b; case 4: a=a/b; default: a=a; } printf('%d', a);",
    answer: "d.) None of above",
    options: [
      "a.) 7",
      "b.) 5",
      "c.) 2",
      "d.) None of above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "A ________ operator applies to two operands, while a _______ operator applies to a single operand.",
    answer: "a.) Binary, Unary",
    options: [
      "a.) Binary, Unary",
      "b.) Ternary, Binary",
      "c.) Unary, Ternary",
      "d.) None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "A ________ is a place where we can store values. Size of INT is ____________ bits.",
    answer: "d.) int, 16",
    options: [
      "a.) int, 2",
      "b.) variable, 16",
      "c.) variable, 2",
      "d.) int, 16"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which is the step by step representation of program creation?",
    answer: "a.) Algorithm",
    options: [
      "a.) Algorithm",
      "b.) Dry Run",
      "c.) Flow Chart",
      "d.) None of Above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Dry Run is a __________.",
    answer: "c.) Step by Step Development",
    options: [
      "a.) Tabular Development",
      "b.) Graphical Representation",
      "c.) Step by Step Development",
      "d.) None of Above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "'B' language is developed by___________.",
    answer: "b.) Dennis Ritchie",
    options: [
      "a.) Martin Richards",
      "b.) Dennis Ritchie",
      "c.) Ken Thompson",
      "d.) Berian Kerningham"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which is not the graphical representation of program creation?",
    answer: "d.) (A) and (B) both",
    options: [
      "a.) Algorithm",
      "b.) Dry Run",
      "c.) Flow Chart",
      "d.) (A) and (B) both"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "ANSI C permits the use of as many as ________ case labels.",
    answer: "d.) 256",
    options: [
      "a.) 258",
      "b.) 259",
      "c.) 257",
      "d.) 256"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Structure template is terminated by symbol _____________.",
    answer: "a.) Semicolon ( ; )",
    options: [
      "a.) Semicolon ( ; )",
      "b.) Comma ( , )",
      "c.) Space ( )",
      "d.) Underscore ( _ )"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "? : is ______________ operator.",
    answer: "d.) Conditional",
    options: [
      "a.) Logical",
      "b.) Bitwise",
      "c.) Assignment",
      "d.) Conditional"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which symbol is used to define an array?",
    answer: "a.) [ ]",
    options: [
      "a.) [ ]",
      "b.) { }",
      "c.) < >",
      "d.) ( )"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "pow(), abs() & sqrt() are situated in ______________ header file.",
    answer: "d.) math.h",
    options: [
      "a.) stdio.h, math.h, ctype.h",
      "b.) string.h",
      "c.) ctype.h",
      "d.) math.h"
    ]
  }
];